## **ASOH NOELLE-ESTHER**

## Information Systems and Networking Engineer

+237681006451 - asohne.km@gmail.com - Yaounde, Cameroon

#### Summary

I am a confident, hardworking and self motivated Information Systems and Networking student. I have led successful school projects, managed information systems and controlled the network systems of companies. I am looking forward to leverage my knowledge and experience into a role as an Information Systems and Networking Engineer.

#### Education

COSBIE Complex, GCE Ordinary Level Mario Academic Complex, GCE Advanced Level

ICT University, BSc. Information Systems and Networking Yaounde, Cameroon September 2018 - June 2019 Yaounde, Cameroon September 2019 - June 2021

> Yaounde, Cameroon October 2021 - Present

### Skills

- Microsoft Word, Excel, Outlook and Powerpoint
- Programming in python
- Web design Html & CSS
- Copywriting
- Critical thinking and problem solving

- TCP/IP
- Static routing
- VLAN switching
- Time management
- Problem-solving

#### Experience

# Zenithe Insurance IT intern

Douala, Cameroon June 2022 - August 2022

- Examined and revised procedures, standards, and guidelines documents using tools like Microsoft word
- Generated regular reports
- Troubleshooted and resolved hardware and software issues, including operating systems, printers, and mobile devices
- Assisted in the relocation of the IT infrastructure of the company
- Assisted in the design and implementation of the network system in the new office building
- Participated in the configuration and maintenance of static routing for network contexts, like local area networks
- Gained knowledge of various security devices and technologies to ensure network security and prevent unauthorized access.
- Prior to relocating, I participated in a full examination of existing security measures and identified flaws in the IT system

United Bank for Africa (UBA) IT intern

Yaounde, Cameroon July 2023 - Present

- Generated regular reports
- Gained knowledge of the implementation of static routing solutions to optimize network traffic
- Configured and maintained Cisco routers and switches for multiple clients, ensuring reliable network performance and security
- Troubleshooted and resolved hardware and software issues, including operating systems, printers, and mobile devices
- Participated in vulnerability assessments and penetration testing for specific networks and servers
- Participated in the configuration and maintenance of network equipment such as routers, switches, and firewalls to ensure peak performance and security

### Languages

- English
- French

# Interests & Hobbies

- Reading
- Researching
- Singing